ANA STATE

UX|UI & VOICE DESIGNER



SUMMARY

I'm a User Experience/ Voice Designer with a background in engineering & Computer Science. Having an interest for various industries kept me interchanging processes from one field to another, trying to find innovative solutions to diverse problems. I believe great design comes from the intersection of different fields and teams, enabling people to build together something indeed meaningful.

SKILLS SET

- Strategy: Design thinking, Design sprint facilitation, Lean UX.
- Research: User | stakeholders interviews, usability & A/B testing Personas & Empathy mapping.
- Design: Wireframing, Prototyping, Motion Design

TOOLS

- Sketch, Figma
- Invision, InDesign,
- Principle, Flinto
- draw.io, Balsamiq
- Abstract, Zeplin
- Webflow, Adobe XD
- Slack, Trello

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior UX|UI Designer

BCR Erste - Bucharest

07/2018 - Present

eToken Redesign Project

- Lead the end-to end UX/UI design from User Research to Prototyping & Visual design, facilitating design sprints.
- Conducted in person-interviews to understand how people sign & authorise transactions within the current design in order to determine friction points
- Used user interviews insights to create Personas / Storyboard that map users' needs with business goals of the project and draw the app's redesign strategy
- Used Prototypes to validate design decisions via A/B & Usability testing

Sales meets Analystics & Data Science Project

- Analysed the existing cross-selling process to identify pain points both the sales agents and the customer are faced with
- Conducted in person-interviews in branches to understand how sales agents use the current software tools to build customer profiles and sell products
- Used the insights gathered from User research to build Personas / Storyboard that outline sales agents' needs, current user journey and map this data with the business goals of the project.
- Team up with data science team to draw the design strategy for the new tools based on the machine learning model built by them and research data gathered from user research

Freelance UX|UI Designer

Freelance Projects

04/2017 - Present

Ink Tank

- Conducted competitive analysis to understand the tattoo market & other existing apps
- Lead the end-to end UX/UI design from User Research to wireframing,prototyping & visual design.

EDUCATION

CAREER FOUNDRY

2018 - 2019

UX | UI & Voice Design

POLITECHNICA UNIVERSITY

2012 - 2014

MS Information Engineering & Computer Science

POLITECHNICA UNIVERSITY

2008 - 2012

BS Applied Electronics, Telecommunicati ons & Information Technology

SELF TAUGHT ON

- HTMI
- CSS
- WEBFLOW
- CSS FLEXBOX
- MySQL
- Linux
- Any design tool I use

OTHER SKILLS

I am multilingual and can speak English, Spanish, Italian, Romanian, and I am also learning Dutch.

- Created the design system that outlined styles for the entire app.
- Collaborated with a front-end developer to implement the code of the app

Release Implementation Manager

KPN - Amsterdam

06/2018 - 12/2018

Future of Mobile Project

- Lead the cross functional Release implementation process for multiple projects (migrations, monthly releases, application upgrades) for a web platform serving over 2 million subscribers
- Simplified the end-to end implementation process reducing the implementation time by 20%, through effective collaboration with business stakeholders, QA, and engineering team

Technical Change Manager

Huawei Technologies - Amsterdam

11/2015 - 05/2018

CCBS 2.0 Telfort Project

- Oversaw the implementation of 30 + upgrade projects, feature changes, maintenance projects of a 2 million end users web platform
- Connect client/business goals and user needs to the SA team, working closely with engineers and managing the Agile process to maximise value delivery for each implementation

Back-office Software Engineer

Huawei Technologies

05/2014 - 11/2015

Arrow Project

- Designed automated scenarios and performed UAT testing via digital channels to validate the usability of the new software features and decide which feature goes to Production environment
- Provided technical fault management and support on a Production platform serving 29 client shops & their end users